# Jun Xing (邢骏)

junxnui@gmail.com, http://junxnui.github.io

# RESEARCH

My research combines modern concepts in computer graphics, computer vision, machine learning and human computer interaction, with broad applications in 2D/3D digital contents analysis, synthesis and authoring. In particular, I am interested in *interactive/predictive* modeling and *deep learning-based* reconstruction of high-fidelity face, hair and body for digital human.

# **EDUCATION**

| University of Hong Kong                              | 2012.09 — 2016.12 |
|--|-------------------|
| PhD in computer science, advised by Dr. Li-Yi Wei    |                   |
| University of Science and Technology of China (USTC) | 2008.09-2012.06   |
| Bachelor in Electronic Engineering and Information   |                   |

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

| USC Institute for Creative Technologies                       | 2017.05—ongoing   |
|---|-------------------|
| Postdoctoral researcher, Vision and Graphics Lab, Los Angeles |                   |
| Adobe Research  | 2016.07 — 2016.09 |
| Audue Research  | 2010.07 2010.09   |
| Graphics research intern, Procedural Imaging Group, San Jose  |                   |
|   |                   |
| Autodesk Research   | 2016.01 - 2016.04 |
| HCI Graphics research intern, UI Group, Toronto               |                   |
|   |                   |
| Microsoft Research Asia                                       | 2014.12 - 2015.04 |
| Graphics research intern, Visual Computing Group, Beijing     |                   |

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### [10] paGAN: Real-time Avatars Using Dynamic Textures

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, *Jun Xing*, Lingyu Wei, Zimo Li, Shunsuke Saito, Aviral Agarwal, Jens Fursund, Hao Li *SIGGRAPH Asia 2018* 

#### [9] HairNet: Single-View Hair Reconstruction using Convolutional Neural Networks

Yi Zhou, Liwen Hu, *Jun Xing*, Weikai Chen, Han-Wei Kung, Xin Tong, Hao Li *ECCV 2018* 

#### [8] Deep Volumetric Video from Very Sparse Multi-View Performance Capture

Zeng Huang, Tianye Li, Weikai Chen, Yajie Zhao, *Jun Xing*, Chloe LeGendre, Linjie Luo, Chongyang Ma, Hao Li *ECCV 2018* 

#### [7] Identity Preserving Face Completion for Large Ocular Region Occlusion

Yajie Zhao, Weikai Chen, *Jun Xing*, Xiaoming Li, Zach Bessinger, Fuchang Liu, Wangmeng Zuo, Ruigang Yang *BMVC 2018* 

# [6] Autocomplete 3D Sculpting

Mengqi Peng, *Jun Xing*, Li-Yi Wei *SIGGRAPH 2018* 

#### [5] Mesoscopic Facial Geometry Inference using Deep Neural Networks

Loc Huynh, Weikai Chen, Shunsuke Saito, *Jun Xing*, Koki Nagano, Andrew Jones, Hao Li, Paul Debevec *CVPR 2018 (Spotlight)* 

### [4] Sequence-to-Sequence Learning via Shared Latent Representation

Xu Shen, Xinmei Tian, *Jun Xing*, Yong Rui, Dacheng Tao *AAAI 2018* 

#### [3] Energy-Brushes: Interactive Tools for Illustrating Stylized Elemental Dynamics

Jun Xing, Rubaiat Habib Kazi, Tovi Grossman, Li-Yi Wei, Jos Stam, George Fitzmaurice UIST 2016

### [2] Autocomplete Hand-drawn Animations

Jun Xing, Li-Yi Wei, Takaaki Shiratori, and Koji Yatani SIGGRAPH Asia 2015

#### [1] Autocomplete Painting Repetitions

Jun Xing, Hsiang-Ting Chen and Li-Yi Wei SIGGRAPH Asia 2014

#### **EXHIBITIONS**

#### Deep Learning-Based Photoreal Avatars for Online Virtual Worlds in iOS

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, *Jun Xing*, Kyle San, Aaron Hong, Mclean Goldwhite, Jiale Kuang, Aviral Agarwal, Caleb Arthur, Hanwei Kung, Stuti Rastogi, Carrie Sun, Stephen Chen, Jens Fursund, Hao Li. SIGGRAPH 2018 Real-time Live!

#### MORE RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Strip-based Hair Modeling in VR

2017.08 — ongoing

We provide a 3D VR authoring interface for immersive interaction with the hair models. Our system combines the flexibility of manual authoring, the convenience of data-driven automation for high quality hair modeling.

#### Autocomplete VR painting

2016.07 - ongoing

The goal is to handle different types of repetitions in VR painting, including the detail decorative strokes, the surface strokes, and even higher-level scaffold, in a simple and general framework.

# **Interactive Facial Hair Editing and Synthesis**

2017.06—ongoing

Users can design facial hairs of different shapes/lengths/densities via simple sketching, while keeping the style of a target facial hair defined by an exemplar image.

#### **Perspective Undistortion of Unconstrained Portrait Photos**

2018.03—ongoing

We present a deep learning-based approach specially tailored for rectifying the facial distortion in an unconstrained portrait image.

#### **Quantization Network**

2018.02—ongoing

We present a simple/straightforward and general/uniform solution for any-bit weights and activations quantization, yet achieving higher performance than state-of-the-arts.

#### **PATENTS**

#### **Techniques for Generating Dynamic Effects Animations**

US filed by Autodesk (2016)

#### Stroke Operation Prediction for Three-Dimensional Digital Content

US filed by Adobe (2017)

#### ACADEMIC SERVICE

#### **Committee Member:**

**AAAI 2019** 

International Conference on Computational Visual Media (CVM) 2019

Pacific Graphics 2018

SIGGRAPH Emerging Technology 2017

#### **Reviewer:**

SIGGRAPH Asia 2017; CHI 2017; PG 2015, 2016; Computer & Graphics 2017;

IEEE Transactions on Cognitive and Developmental Systems 2017;

IEEE Computer Graphics and Applications 2016;

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

# **Designer:**

algorithm, system, UI/UX

# **Programmer:**

C/C++, Qt, Python, Java, OpenGL/CV/VR, Unity

# **AWARDS**

| Adobe Research Fellowship Finalist  | 2016       |  |
|---|------------|--|
| Excellent intern of Stars of Tomorrow Internship Program, Microsoft Research Asia | 2015       |  |
| HKU University Postgraduate Fellowships, HKU                                      | 2012-2015  |  |
| Outstanding undergraduate, USTC   | 2012       |  |
| Outstanding undergraduate research project, USTC                                  | 2011       |  |
| Second prize in Mathematical Contest in Modeling                                  | 2011       |  |
| National Scholarship, Ministry of Education, China                                | 2011       |  |
| National Inspirational Scholarship, Ministry of Education, China                  | 2009, 2010 |  |
| Outstanding Students Scholarship, USTC  | 2008, 2009 |  |
|   |            |  |

# **REFERENCES**

Dr. Li-Yi WeiAdobe Research, lwei@adobe.comDr. Hao LiPinscreen, USC, ICT, hao@hao-li.comDr. Rubaiat Habib KaziAdobe Research, rhabib@adobe.com

**Dr. Tovi Grossman** Autodesk Research and University of Toronto, tovi@dgp.toronto.edu